Fern loved Wilbur more than anything.
She loved to stroke him, to feed him, to put him to bed. Every morning, as soon
as she got up, she warmed his milk, tied his bib on, and held the bottle for him.
Every afternoon, when the school bus stopped in front of her house, she
jumped out and ran to the kitchen to fix another bottle for him.
She fed him again at supper time, and again just before going to bed. Mrs.
Arable gave him a feeding around noon time each day when Fern was away in school.
Wilbur loved his milk, and he was never happier than when Fern was warming up a
bottle for him. He would stand and gaze up at her with adoring eyes.
For the first few days of his life, Wilbur was allowed to live in a box near
the stove in the kitchen. Then, when Mrs. Arable complained, he was moved to
a bigger box in the woodshed. At two weeks of age, he was moved outdoors. It
was apple blossom time, and the days were getting warmer. Mr. Arable fixed a
small yard specially for Wilbur, under an apple tree, and gave him a large
wooden box full of straw with a doorway
cut in it so he could walk in and out as he pleased.
"Won't he be cold at night?" asked Fern.
"No," said her father. You watch and see what he does. Carrying a bottle of milk,
Fern sat down under the apple tree inside the yard. Wilbur ran to her and
she held the bottle for him while he sucked. When he had finished the last
drop, he grunted and walked sleepily into the box.
Fern peered through the door. Wilbur was poking the straw with his snout. In a
short time, he had dug a tunnel in the straw. He crawled into the tunnel and
disappeared from sight, completely covered with straw. Fern was enchanted.
It relieved her mind to know that her baby would sleep covered up and would stay warm.
Every morning after breakfast, Wilbur walked out to the road with Fern and
waited with her till the bus came. She would wave goodbye to him and he would
stand and watch the bus until it vanished around a turn. While Fern was
in school, Wilbur was shut up inside his yard. But as soon as she got home in the
afternoon, she would take him out and he would follow her around the place.
If she went into the house, Wilbur went too. If she went upstairs, Wilbur would
wait at the bottom step until she came down again. If she took her doll for a
walk in the doll carriage, Wilbur followed along. Sometimes on these
journeys, Wilbur would get tired and Fern would pick him up and put him in
the carriage alongside the doll. He liked this.
And if he was very tired, he would close his eyes and go to sleep under the
doll's blanket. He looked cute when his eyes were closed because his lashes were
so long. The doll would close her eyes, too, and Fern would wheel the carriage
very slowly and smoothly so as not to wake her infants.
One warm afternoon, Fern and Avery put on bathing suits and went down to the
brook for a swim. Wilbur tagged along at Fern's heels. When she waited into the
brook, Wilbur waited in with her. He found the water quite cold, too cold for
his liking. So while the children swam and played and splashed water at each
other, Wilbur amused himself in the mud along the edge of the brook, where it
was warm and moist and delightfully sticky and oozy.
Every day was a happy day, and every night was peaceful.
Wilbur was what farmers call a spring pig, which simply means that he was born
in springtime. When he was 5 weeks old, Mr. Arable said he was now big enough to
sell and would have to be sold. Fern broke down and wept, but her father was
firm about it. Wilbur's appetite had increased. He was beginning to eat
scraps of food in addition to milk. Mr.
Arable was not willing to provide for him any longer. He had already sold
Wilbur's 10 brothers and sisters.
He's got to go, Fern, he said. You've had your fun raising a baby pig, but
Wilbur is not a baby any longer, and he has got to be sold. Call up the
Zuckermanman's, suggested Mrs. Arable to Fern. Your uncle Homer sometimes raises
a pig, and if Wilbur goes there to live, you can walk down the road and visit him
as often as you like. "How much money should I ask for him?" Fern wanted to
know. "Well," said her father, "He's a runt, tell your uncle Homer, you've got
a pig you'll sell for $6 and see what he says."
It was soon arranged. Fern phoned and got her aunt Edith. And her aunt Edith
hollered for Uncle Homer. And Uncle Homer came in from the barn and talked
to Fern. When he heard that the price was only $6, he said he would buy the
pig. Next day, Wilbur was taken from his home under the apple tree and went to
live in a manure pile in the cellar of Zuckerman's barn.
Chapter 3.
escape.
[Music]